<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" ><generator uri="https://jekyllrb.com/" version="4.3.1">Jekyll</generator><link href="http://localhost:4000/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/atom+xml" /><link href="http://localhost:4000/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" /><updated>2024-02-19T11:54:49-05:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/feed.xml</id><title type="html">landon.gray.me</title><subtitle>stay curious</subtitle><author><name>Landon Gray</name></author><entry><title type="html">Passive Compassion</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/passive-compassion" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Passive Compassion" /><published>2024-02-19T00:00:00-05:00</published><updated>2024-02-19T00:00:00-05:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/passive-compassion</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/passive-compassion"><![CDATA[<p>There is nothing worse than passive compassion.</p>

<p>Sometimes compassion means getting angry on behalf of someone else and taking a stand.</p>

<p>If a bully is bullying others on the playground and you “feel bad” about the person being bullied, but choose to do nothing…</p>

<p><strong>…that is not compassion, you that is passivity.</strong></p>

<p>Compassion is hard and uncomfortable because real compassion pushes you to take action.</p>

<p>Recently, I met a young man in my community. He looked a little rough; he was homeless, had a mother on drugs, and told me he had been stabbed several times in the past. His hope, he told me, was that he wouldn’t be strung out on drugs like some members of his family.</p>

<p>I gave this man a ride…</p>

<p>Why? Because I saw in this man myself and all the absurdities I’ve faced and seen in my own life as a Black man in this country. To see him there and to hear his story cut me open inside and made me incredibly angry. My compassion for this man took the form of anger because the injustice done to him did not occur today…no, no…it’s been happening since his ancestors and my ancestors stepped off the ship into this unknown land.</p>

<p>There is seldom a day that goes by that I am not aware of the injustice that has befallen so many whose stories relate to this man.</p>

<p>One cannot be absolved of the wrongdoing one sees without taking some sort of action. It is not enough to just feel for the person who was wronged; you must do something.</p>

<p><strong>Celebrating Black History Month, to me, means remaining conscious and aware of the injustices that have befallen and still fall upon Black bodies.</strong></p>

<p><strong>To celebrate Black History Month means acknowledging the wrongs, seeing the progress, and finding productive ways to be angry and to honor the struggle of those who came before me.</strong></p>

<p>To be conscious while Black in this country is an incredibly burdensome task, as James Baldwin so eloquently describes…</p>

<blockquote>
  <p>To be a Negro in this country and to be relatively conscious is to be in a state of rage almost, almost all of the time — and in one’s work. And part of the rage is this: It isn’t only what is happening to you. But it’s what’s happening all around you and all of the time in the face of the most extraordinary and criminal indifference, indifference of most white people in this country, and their ignorance. Now, since this is so, it’s a great temptation to simplify the issues under the illusion that if you simplify them enough, people will recognize them. I think this illusion is very dangerous because, in fact, it isn’t the way it works. A complex thing can’t be made simple. You simply have to try to deal with it in all its complexity and hope to get that complexity across. 
~ <nobr>James Baldwin</nobr></p>
</blockquote>

<p><strong>Source:</strong> <a href="https://www.npr.org/2020/06/01/867153918/-to-be-in-a-rage-almost-all-the-time">NPR</a></p>

<p>And yet, one must be conscious no matter the cost, despite the pain, because of the pain…and it is indeed through remaining conscious and taking action that any hope of alleviating suffering can occur.</p>

<p>I am so incredibly grateful to people like Harriet Tubman, Malcolm X, MLK, Aretha Franklin, Ta-Nehisi Coates, James Baldwin, and so many others whose lives have encouraged me to press on, be brave, resist passivity, and to remain steadfast and clear about who I am in this world.</p>

<p>My hope is that one day we as a society will overcome this great sickness of indifference that plagues us now. That we will gather together and affirm our collective desire to see a better world.</p>

<p>This hope is best embodied in the lines of this old Negro spiritual:</p>

<p><a href="https://youtu.be/MgwG802rHng?t=35">We shall overcome, we shall overcome…we shall overcome one day!</a></p>]]></content><author><name>Landon Gray</name></author><category term="compassion" /><summary type="html"><![CDATA[There is nothing worse than passive compassion.]]></summary><media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="http://localhost:4000/compassion-needed.png" /><media:content medium="image" url="http://localhost:4000/compassion-needed.png" xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" /></entry><entry><title type="html">Life after cron job</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/life-after-cron-jobs" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Life after cron job" /><published>2023-08-08T00:00:00-04:00</published><updated>2023-08-08T00:00:00-04:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/life-after-cron-jobs</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/life-after-cron-jobs"><![CDATA[<p>One of my new found interests besides ML stuff is Data Engineering.</p>

<p>One interesting thing I hope to explore more is the way various ways organizations handle scheduling jobs.</p>

<p>Obviously <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Cron">cron</a> is a pretty solid initial step, but <a href="https://engblog.nextdoor.com/we-don-t-run-cron-jobs-at-nextdoor-6f7f9cc62040">it doesn’t scale well at all</a>. One frustration with cron at scale is that it always runs at a specified time. If a job  runs 1 minute longer than expected it will cause all subsequent dependent jobs to fail (since they are dependent on the task to complete before they run)</p>

<p>Unfortunately to fix such failures costs developer time and effort. Not to mention it could cause unwanted downstream issues in dev, stage and prod environments… OH NO!</p>

<p>So how do we manage these dependencies?</p>

<p>Well, to fix these issues we need to better understand the dependencies these jobs have with one another and clearly map them out.</p>

<p>Using <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Directed_acyclic_graph">DAGs</a> ( Directed Acyclic Graphs) we can clearly map these dependencies.</p>

<p><img src="/assets/img/example-dag.png" alt="Directed Acyclic Graph example" /></p>

<p><em>Credit Wikipedia</em></p>

<p>Once we are finished, we can then elicit the help of a <strong>Workflow Scheduling Framework</strong> to run the tasks in order as part of a single workflow.</p>

<p>In addition to preventing failures due to long running tasks, these set of tasks will run faster since they can run as soon as the dependent task finishes instead of waiting until it’s scheduled time.</p>

<p>3 industry standard workflow management tools that can help us here are:</p>

<ul>
  <li><a href="https://airflow.apache.org/">Apache Airflow</a> created by Airbnb</li>
  <li><a href="https://oozie.apache.org/">Oozie</a> (also apache)</li>
  <li><a href="https://github.com/spotify/luigi">Luigi</a> created by Spotify</li>
</ul>

<p>This is by no means an exhausive list, there are no doubt many more.</p>

<p>But this should be enough for you to get started. If you happen to have any questions come up feel free to email me 😃</p>]]></content><author><name>Landon Gray</name></author><category term="data-engineering" /><summary type="html"><![CDATA[One of my new found interests besides ML stuff is Data Engineering.]]></summary><media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="http://localhost:4000/cron-clock.jpg" /><media:content medium="image" url="http://localhost:4000/cron-clock.jpg" xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" /></entry><entry><title type="html">Practical Thoughts on Work Sustainability</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/practical-thoughts-on-work-sustainability" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Practical Thoughts on Work Sustainability" /><published>2023-02-11T00:00:00-05:00</published><updated>2023-02-11T00:00:00-05:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/practical-thoughts-on-work-sustainability</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/practical-thoughts-on-work-sustainability"><![CDATA[<p>As a teenager and in my young adult years I spent much of my time at school (work), volunteering (work) studying (work), playing sports(work), working a summer job (work), etc…</p>

<p>Though the only times these felt like work was when I didn’t want to do them.</p>

<p>Progressively I find myself taking on more and more, yet I often feel like I’m working less and less.</p>

<p>But that begs the question…If you like what you do, are you even working anymore?</p>

<p>And the question I’m most interested in is this: <b> Is number of hours worked a good measure of predicatability as to whether someone is going to experience burnout? </b></p>

<p>To be fair I’m pretty sure the answer is a somewhat yes. YIKES!</p>

<p><img src="/assets/img/google-burnout.png" alt="Indicator of burnout" /></p>

<p>That being said, we know from stats class that <b> correlation ≠ causation </b></p>

<p>And we have countless counter examples of people who are so passionate about their work that they will pour absurd amounts of time to improve their craft or business with very few visible signs of burnout.</p>

<p>And let’s be honest…If this is the litmus for what healthy sustainable work is supposed to be then most graduate school programs would never pass the test. And you could never do anything like work a full time job and go back to school or earn a certificate at the same time without violating some univeral law of burnout.</p>

<p>There seems to be more talk about the number of hours worked and not enough discussion about the sustainability of the work. I recon if you have bad managers, mean coworkers and short hours you will burn out a lot faster than the person happily working 50 hours a week in their dream job.</p>

<p><b> Burnout is not simply a function of the number of hours worked but also the intensity of the work and the desire (or lack thereof) to do the work. Bad managers and mean coworkers would in theory decrease ones desire to be at work and would also make getting work done harder. </b></p>

<p>Beyond what society deems healthy and acceptable we all have our own internal tolerance of what we each are willing or able to endure. Spending 20 hours a week on something I don’t want to do is 5x harder than spending 35-50 hours on something I enjoy doing or find meaningful.</p>

<p>Maybe we should start talking less about the # of hours worked and more about whether or not those hours are meaningful and sustainable for people. ie: if I need to work 50 hours and want to … is that really all that bad?</p>

<p>For me, <b>#workaholism</b> has always been about the inability (sometimes caused by work) to set or enforce boundaries between work activities and engagements outside of work to the point that it spills into other facet of your life. ie: it bleeds into your family time, community time, extra circulars, etc… If you work 60 hours and want to and also have enough time to live life as you please I’d say that is a pretty sustainable “work life balance”. Do you agree?</p>]]></content><author><name>Landon Gray</name></author><category term="work" /><category term="career" /><summary type="html"><![CDATA[As a teenager and in my young adult years I spent much of my time at school (work), volunteering (work) studying (work), playing sports(work), working a summer job (work), etc…]]></summary><media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="http://localhost:4000/balance.jpg" /><media:content medium="image" url="http://localhost:4000/balance.jpg" xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" /></entry><entry><title type="html">About the Author</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/about" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="About the Author" /><published>2022-11-25T00:00:00-05:00</published><updated>2022-11-25T00:00:00-05:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/about</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/about"><![CDATA[<p>Hey I’m Landon Gray,</p>

<p>I’m a software engineer and consultant working at Test Double. I enjoy reading, learning new things and contemplating existence among other things.</p>

<p>This blog is a living work in progress and it is an attempt to both own my own piece of the web and consolidate the information I am learning into a tangible artifact that I and others can learn from.</p>]]></content><author><name>Landon Gray</name></author><category term="journal" /><category term="about" /><summary type="html"><![CDATA[Hey I’m Landon Gray,]]></summary><media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="http://localhost:4000/monkeying-around.png" /><media:content medium="image" url="http://localhost:4000/monkeying-around.png" xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" /></entry></feed>